Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rishabhnmishra (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Science
Data Analytics
Machine Learning

Languages

Hindi (Full Professional) English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Applied Machine Learning in Python SQL Bootcamp
Google Data Analytics Specialization
Applied Data Science with Python
Specialization

Tableau for Data Science

Honors-Awards

Gold Badge for SQL Gold Badge for Python

Rishabh Mishra

Sr. Data Analyst | 240K+ Subs @ YouTube | Google Certified | 5+ Years in Data Science & Analytics | Teacher

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Senior Data Analyst with over 5.5 years of experience in the field of data science & analytics, accompanied by a bachelor's degree in engineering and a Google certified data analytics specialization. My professional journey has spanned diverse sectors including retail, ecommerce, Banking, digital media/advertising and marketing.

Key Skills: Data science, Data analytics, Statistical analysis, Hypothesis Testing, Predictive Analytics, Problem Solving, Machine learning, NLP and Project management

Languages: SQL, Python, R, HTML

Database: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Snowflake, MySQL,

SQLite, AWS Athena, AWS Redshift, Google Big Query

Other: Excel, AWS Cloud, Google cloud, Git, Bitbucket, JIRA, Digital marketing, Web Analytics and Google Analytics, Databricks, Vertex AI.

Also, a Content Creator & Educator on YouTube where I provide beginner-friendly tutorials and in-depth case studies (projects) on various data science and analytics topics.

YouTube Channel link: www.youtube.com/ @RishabhMishraOfficial

mail: Rmishra.connect@gmail.com

Experience

Merkle Senior Data Analyst May 2021 - Present (3 years 1 month) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Developed ARIMA and SARIMA time series forecasting model to predict sales with 91% accuracy, enabling optimal monthly budget allocation for marketing.
- Used advanced SQL queries to identify credit score risks and delinquency patterns. Recommended integration of debt management tool and 30+ financial education blogs on website and in email campaigns for at-risk segments. Reduced delinquencies by 0.5% in 3 months.
- Developed an ETL process to migrate the data from multiple vendors into a centralised database. Achieving a significant 20% reduction in the data processing time and 95% data accuracy.
- Built and optimized machine learning models regression and clustering for financial data
- Build an automated one-click insights generation dashboard using Python and SQL, reduced manual work by 90% and saved annual cost of \$150K
- Designed and maintained the dashboards to communicate insights and monitor products performance across various KPIs.

iQuanti, Inc.

2 years 8 months

Senior Data Analyst

April 2020 - May 2021 (1 year 2 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka

- Performed marketing analytics, data extraction, data manipulation, big data analysis and shared insights with stakeholders
- Designed and executed A/B tests, performed rigorous statistical analysis. Led to 20% MoM increase in the conversion rate
- Developed attribution model and multi-channel funnel report, . Led to a notable decrease in churn rate 3% YoY
- Web analytics- Analyzed paid ad campaigns and ensured timely delivery of post-campaign reports, findings and recommendations.
- Ownership of projects for offshore clients and mentorship to new joiners

Data Analyst

October 2018 - April 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

- Developed ETL pipelines to collect, manage and analyze dataset, boosting productivity by 25%.
- Analysing marketplace, creating important metrics and identifying potential sources of opportunities.
- Online brand building and marketing strategy for US-based BFSI and retail clients
- Weekly & monthly reporting and dashboards using Tableau and Data Studio

Textron

Design and Analysis Intern January 2018 - June 2018 (6 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Full-time internship at Textron:

- Support for CAE dept in a model setup using CAE tools Hyper mesh and Ansys
- Design and analysis of HDP fuel tanks and plastic models for top 5 automobile companies around the world on their future projects

Education

Visvesvaraya Technological University

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Mechanical Engineering · (2014 - 2018)

Coursera

Google Data Analytics Professional Course (October 2022 - January 2023)

Army Public School (APS)

Higher Secondary School, Science-Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics